EDUARDO CRUZ

SENIOR FULL STACK DEVELOPER

Download PDF

eduardo@eduardocruz.com

+55 (81) 9197-9035

Profile

18 years of experience in software development. In the last four years, as an entrepreneur, I have split my time between: business management, project management and coding.

Skills

Sw. Development

Started coding in 1994 and never stopped. From desktop to web and from flowcharts to agile practices.

Management

Beetween 2007 and 2013 have worked as: team leader, project manager and agile consultant.

Business

Between 2007 and 2013 have worked with: business presentations, business proposals, research funding and contract negotiation.

Technical

Java Certified Developer	PMI Agile Certified Practitioner	Sw Engineering Master Degree
Backend Developer	Continuous Integration	LAMP
Front-End Developer	Software Architecture	Lean Startup

Experience

Mobciti.com Full Stack Developer

2012-Present

Mobciti has an embedded/mobile solution to track buses in Recife that also streams music and advertisement. They needed someone to validate their architecture, manage software development and also create new features for their mobile/web solution.

Industry.: Public Transportaion

Recife, Brazil

MvSkills.com.br Pet Project

2012-Present

Myskills is my personal side project to put in practice front-end, back-end and mobile technologies and also keep in touch with the software development community. It is a software developer ranking system that uses badges and technology checkins to map software development skills.

Industry.: Software Development

Recife, Brazil

Porto Digital **Board Member**

2011-Present

Since 2011 I am a board member of Porto Digital representing the incubated startups. We meet every quarter to discuss financial and strategical issues of the cluster.

Industry.: Software Development

Recife, Brazil

RHoK (Random Hacks of Kindness) Event Organizer/Hackaton Coder

2012-2012

In order to bring awareness to the software development community to its potential, in 2012 I organized the event RHoK 2012. Random Hacks of Kindness (RHoK) is a community of developers, geeks and tech-savvy do-gooders around the world, working to develop software solutions that respond to the challenges facing humanity today.

Industry.: Social Good

RiSE Software Reuse Residency Course Coordinator

2011-2012

The Software Reuse Residency was a software engineering course with 450 hours (one year) of theory and practice in Porto Digital for 20 students who received a scholarship sponsored by CNPq (Conselho Nacional de Desenvolvimento Científico e Tecnológico) and also with a partnership with Porto Digital. I wrote the project and submitted to CNPq, and also presented some lectures and manage another 10 different teachers with disciplines such as: software engineering, software reuse, software architecture, software product lines and testing and so on. *Industry.: Education*

RiSE (Reuse in Software Engineer) Founder

2010-2013

In 2004 the research group RiSE (Reuse in Software Engineer) started in UFPE discussing and researching software reuse and productivity. In 2010 we founded the company which has worked with software development trainning and consulting since them. As a founder I had to work with business management, business development, project management, trainning and

Industry.: Software Development

Recife, Brazil

consulting.

Recife, Brazil

CESAR (Centro de Estudos e Sistemas Avançados do Recife)

2005-2010

Many Roles

During my five years at CESAR, each year I have worked in a different role. I started as a java web developer, them became team leader, after that project manager, business manager and finally as a teacher and course coordinator in software development courses.

Industry.: Software Development

Recife, Brazil

JavaBahia

2003-2005

User Group Founder

In order to improve the software development community in Salvador I founded the first Java Community User Group in the city, which achieved about 600 developers who discussed online and also organized events with tech talks.

Industry.: Software Development

Salvador, Brazil

Sysdesign 2001-2004 Oracle Developer

Sysdesign is a Oracle Certified Partner in Bahia. During the four years that I worked there, I had experience with different Oracle technologies like Oracle Database, Oracle Forms and Reports and Oracle Internet Application Server. Working in the Justice Department (Tribunal de Justiça do Estado) during four years I also had to master their domain.

Industry.: Justice Salvador, Brazil

Sociedade Mineira de Catoca

1999-2000

Web Developer

Catoca is the third diamond mine in the world. By that time it was still a war zone and they needed someone to deal with their website, intranet and ERP reports. It was a life-changing experience.

Industry.: Mining Saurimo, Angola

Jornal A Tarde

1998-1999
Web Developer

Jornal A Tarde is the main newspaper in Bahia. In 1998 they started a new business as a Internet Service Provider and they needed someone to develop their website and manage server infrastructure (LAMP - Linux Apache MySQL and PHP)

Industry.: Internet Service Provider

Salvador, Brazil

e-Net Internet Connections Web Developer

1996-1996

e-Net was one of the first Internet Service Providers in Bahia. They needed someone to develop their website and manage server infrastructure (LAMP - Linux Apache MySQL and PHP) Industry.: Internet Service Provider

Salvador, Brazil

1995-1996

P&J Informatica Desktop Developer

First job as a desktop developer creating an Inventory Control System. Working with the following technologies: Clipper Summer 87, Delphi 1.0 and 2.0.

Industry.: Software Development

Salvador, Brazil

Education

Universidade Federal de Pernambuco - Recife, Brazil

Software Engineering Master Degree — ${f 2009}$

Universidade Salvador - Salvador, Brazil Bachelor of Computer Science -2005

Escola Tomaz de Aquino - Salvador, Brazil Technical Software Developer — $\mathbf{1995}$

Stoneham Highschool - Stoneham, USA Exchange Student — $\mathbf{1991}$

Eduardo Cruz — eduardo@eduardocruz.com — +55 (81) 9197-9035